Die.
（パック）死ね
My brain trembles...
（ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ）
脳が―
震える
Puck!
（ナツキ･スバル）パック！
Be quiet, Subaru.
（パック）
黙っていなよ スバル
君だけは別に
I don't care what you—
油断 怠慢 すなわち怠惰
Complacency! Negligence! That is sloth!
You should have killed me right away!
あなたは 私を即座に
仕留めるべきだったのデス
Even with the power you have,
その力がありながら―
you failed to accomplish what you needed to do!
あなたは
なすべきことを―
怠ったのデス！
Foolishness.
（パック）くだらない
If you truly want to kill me...
本気で 僕を
殺したいなら―
Then grow a thousand shadows,
サテラの半分 千は
影を伸ばしてみせろ
a mere half of what Satella could do.
Are you... Puck?
パック… なのか
Shouldn't that be obvious?
（パック）
見れば分かるだろ―
Maybe it's cruel of me to ask that.
というのは いじわるな話か
（ペテルギウス）ありえない
Unbelievable...
This is unbelievable!
こんなことはありえない
あってはならないのデス
It cannot be!
A measly spirit...
ただの精霊が―
My faith...
私の信仰を 愛を捧(ささ)げる全てを
精霊風情が！
My life's labor of love...
At the hands of a measly spirit—
A human who's only lived a few decades
shouldn't talk to a spirit about time.
（パック）
たかだか生まれて
数十年の人間が―
精霊相手に時間を語るな
Time has nothing to do with the depth of one's faith!
（ペテルギウス）
信仰の深さに
時間など関係ないのデス！
I wish you wouldn't liken me
悠久の時を生きるが故に
その大半を無為に浪費する―
to a fool like you—a being that lives for eternity,
あなたのような愚か者と
一緒にしないでもらいたいものデス
but wastes most of it in idleness!
Ah, my brain is tremblinglinglingling...
ああ 脳が震えるるるる…
Death isn't even a punishment.
（パック）
死が 罰にすらならない
This is why I hate all of you.
だから 僕はお前たちが嫌いなんだ
The Ordeal has been completed.
試練は果たされたのデス
Even if my body dies,
この身は朽ちようとも
私の思いは―
尊き魔女の身元へといざなわれ
寵(ちょう)愛に預かる
my wishes will be called to the exalted witch's side.
And I'll receive her love.
I look forward to our reunion!
再会が 楽しみデスね！
アッハッハッハ アッハハ…
He quit while he was ahead.
（パック）勝ち逃げされたな
Now, shall we have a little talk?
さて 話をしようか
Subaru,
スバル 君の罪は３つある
you have committed three sins.
First, you broke your promise to Lia.
１つは リアとの約束を破ったこと
You don't seem to understand
how important a promise is
精霊術師にとって―
結ばれた約束が
どれほど重たいものか―
to a spirit arts user.
君は 理解が足りないらしい
Second, you ignored Lia's
wishes and returned here.
２つ目は リアのお願いを
無視して戻ってきたこと
And third...
そして ３つ目は―
You let Lia die!
リアを死なせたことだ！
In accordance with my contract,
契約に従い
僕はこれから世界を滅ぼす
I will now destroy the world.
Why?
（スバル）どうして…
Lia is...
（パック）リアは―
Emilia is my entire reason for existing.
エミリアは 僕が存在する
理由の全部だ
There is no reason for me
to exist in a world without her.
あの子がいない世界に
僕がいる意味はない
The fog is coming closer.
霧が迫ってくる
It seems a troublesome being has been drawn here.
どうやら やっかいな奴が
呼び寄せられたみたいだ
Gluttony...
暴食
Oh, I suppose they call it the White Whale now.
ああ 今は
白鯨なんて呼ばれ方か
You called it here, let Lia die,
あれを呼び起こし リアを死なせて
自分も命を落として
and now, you die yourself.
You really are useless.
（パック）
本当にどうしようもないんだな 君
I've heard this laugh before.
（スバル）
聞き覚えのある笑い声だ
It's the voice of a man I hated to death.
No...
違う 俺だ 俺を笑ってる
It's me.
I'm laughing at myself.
レムを死なせ エミリアを殺し
自分すらも犬死にする
I let Rem die, killed Emilia,
and now, I'm going to die in vain.
I truly am...
まさに 何とも まあ…
You truly are slothful, Subaru.
（パック）怠惰だね スバル
Subaru-kun?
（レム）
スバルくん どうしたんですか？
What's the matter?
Rem...
レム
（レム）
はい スバルくんのレムです
Yes, I'm your Rem.
I'm sorry I didn't notice.
ごめんなさい 気づかなくて
人混みに疲れてしまったんですね
This crowd is tiring you, isn't it?
Tired.
疲れた…
Yeah, that's right...
ああ そうだな
I'm out of energy, worn to the bone...
落っことして すり切れて
疲れちまったな…
"Tired" is the right word to use.
（スバル）
ハア ハア ハア…
Subaru-kun!
スバルくん！
Sorry about that.
（スバル）ああ 悪かった
I was feeling kind of overwhelmed,
ちょっと 俺も
いろいろ焦ってたんだ
so I skipped over explaining.
それで 説明
はしょっちまった 悪い
Sorry.
Really, you mustn't do that.
（レム）もう 困ります
I realize that you are giving a great
deal of thought to our situation.
スバルくんが
いろいろ考えてくれてるのは―
レムにだって分かっています
Well, not that I dislike when you are forceful.
強引なのも
嫌いじゃありませんけど
Sorry that I worried you.
（スバル）
心配かけてごめんな
もう 大丈夫だ
I'm fine now.
It feels like all you've seen is me
being pathetic, depressed, or both.
ヘコんだり
ヘコまされたりで―
みっともないとこばっか
見せてた気がするけど―
But I have it all figured out now.
やっと分かったから
Have what figured out?
“やっと分かった”ですか？
I've bothered a lot of people with all my contemplating and agonizing,
（スバル）
悩みまくって迷走して
方々に迷惑かけまくったけど―
but I finally figured out how
to take care of everything.
ようやっと 丸く収められる
方法が分かった
Or, when I really think about it,
いや 改めて考えると―
I was told what to do from the very start.
最初から教えてもらってた
はずなんだけど
諦め悪いからなあ 俺
I sure don't know when to give up, do I?
I think that's what makes you so wonderful, though.
そこがスバルくんの
ステキなところだと思いますけど
I've realized some things
and been forced to realize others.
思い知らされたことと
思い知ったことと
Well, the point is, all kinds of experiences have brought me here,
まあ いろんな経験を経て
俺はこうしてるわけだけど
but the answer's actually been
right there for a long time now.
答えは 随分前から
出てたんだよなあ
I've decided, Rem.
決めたんだ レム
はい
Yes?
Run away with me.
（スバル）
俺と一緒に逃げよう
どこまでも
As far as we can go.
Huh?
I'm going to leave the capital and head far west.
（スバル）
これから俺は王都を出て
ずっと西に それか北に向かう
Or maybe north.
Um...
えっと…
I heard no one can enter the southern kingdom,
南の帝国には入れないって
話だから どっちか
so one of those two.
I don't like cold weather,
寒いのは苦手だから
個人的には西が一押しだ
so I'd personally prefer going west.
Ah, um...
いえ あの…
Honestly, it could be a long journey,
ぶっちゃけ 長旅に
なるかも曖昧だし―
and I know this is a snap decision,
見切り発車もいいところだから
楽な旅路には…
so it won't be easy—
P-Please slow down!
（レム）
ま… 待ってください
The way you said that makes it sound as if
（レム）
今のスバルくんの
言い方だと まるで―
you plan to go to some country
other than Lugunica.
ルグニカではない 違う国へ
向かおうとしているような…
あっ スバルくんのこと
ですから―
Oh!
Knowing you, it must be because
you've had another great idea!
ひょっとして 何かまた
すごいことを思いついたんですね？
エミリア様や
ロズワール様の助けになる
Something that will help
Emilia-sama and Roswaal-sama!
That's not what this is, Rem.
（スバル）
そんなもんはねえよ レム
There's nothing I can do in the capital.
王都にいても俺は何もできない
But I'd be just as powerless
if I went back to the mansion.
だからって屋敷に戻ったところで
無力さは変わらない
That's what I figured out.
それが分かったんだよ
So run away with me, Rem.
だから 俺と逃げよう レム
We can't stay here.
ここにいたらダメなんだ
That's what everyone has been telling me.
みんながみんな
俺にそう言い続けた
I didn't want to believe it,
俺はそれを認めたくなくて
必死で否定し続けたけど
so I've denied it with all my might, but...
Yeah, they're right.
ああ そうだよ
No one ever needed me.
誰も俺を必要となんか
しちゃいなかった
そんなこと…
That's not—
ないことはねえよ！
It is true!
It's been spelled out for me, over and over...
ハッキリと言われたんだ
言われ続けたんだ…
That's why I've decided to just disappear.
だから 俺は
いなくなることに決めたんだ
It's for the best.
いいんだよ　俺 なんかが
何かしたところで―
Anything I do will just lead to a dead body...
死体がひとつ 場合によっちゃ
もっと増えるだけだ
Or maybe bodies, depending on what happens.
I've had enough.
もう うんざりだ
Let's run, Rem.
逃げよう レム
You and I can't stay here.
俺もお前もここに…
We shouldn't be in this country!
この国にいちゃいけねえんだ
But this is so sudden...
そんなこと 急に言われても…
We don't have time!
時間がないんだ 突然なのは
ホントに悪いと思ってる
I'm sorry it's sudden, I really am.
I really, really am.
ホントに… ホントにだ
But you have to choose.
でも 選んでくれ
Choose?
選ぶ…
Me? Or someone else?
俺か 俺以外か 選んでくれ
Choose.
Let's get a dragon carriage and head west.
竜車を手に入れて
西へ向かおう
We'll leave Lugunica and go far west...
ルグニカを出て ずっと西
カララギだったか
To Kararagi, was it?
We'll buy a little house and live there together.
そこで小さな家でも買って
２人で暮らすんだ
Even if times are hard,
つらいことがあっても
お前がいればきっと頑張れる
I can keep going if I know you're there.
Just having someone waiting
at home for me with a smile...
誰かが笑顔で
家で待っててくれるだけで―
No matter how tired I am,
どれだけ疲れても―
if I know you're waiting for me, I'm sure...
レムが待っててくれるって
思えば きっと…
Please choose me!
俺を選んでくれ！
俺を選んでくれれば
俺の全てはお前に捧げる
If you choose me, I'll give you all that I have!
So please...
だから―
Run away with me.
俺と逃げよう
俺と生きてくれ
Live with me!
Subaru-kun...
（レム）スバルくん
I cannot run away with you.
レムは スバルくんと
逃げることはできません
We're supposed to laugh together,
だって―
未来のお話は―
as we talk about the future, remember?
笑いながらじゃなきゃ
ダメなんですよ
Maybe we can't laugh now, but...
今は 笑えないかもしれない
けど ほら いざ実行に移してみたら
きっと笑えるはずで…
You know, once we actually get moving,
I bet we can—
I have thought about it too.
（レム）
レムも考えてみました
We would arrive in Kararagi,
カララギに到着して
まず 宿を借ります
and rent a place to stay.
As long as we had a home and work, we would get by somehow.
生活の基盤は 家とお仕事があれば
なんとかなるでしょう
Fortunately, thanks to Roswaal-sama,
I have received an education,
幸い レムは
ロズワール様の計らいで―
教育を受けていますから―
so I think I could easily find work, even in Kararagi.
カララギでも
いくらか仕事を見つけるのは―
容易だと思います
You might have to either look for manual labor
スバルくんは 肉体労働を
探してもらうか―
or help me take care of things.
レムの身の回りのお世話を
してもらうことに―
なるかもしれませんね
Once we had a stable income,
収入が安定したら―
we could look for a better place to live.
もう少し
まともな住居を探しましょう
In the meantime,
スバルくんには その間―
you could study for perhaps a year,
ちゃんとしたお仕事に就くために
勉強してもらって―
so that you can find a decent job
when you're actually able to work.
実際に働けるようになるのに
１年か そのぐらい
We would work together.
２人で働いて ある程度の
お金がたまったら―
And once we had enough money,
perhaps we could buy a house.
家を買っても
いいかもしれませんね
Maybe we could even open a shop.
何かお店をしても
いいかもしれません
After all, Kararagi is a thriving commercial area.
カララギは
商業の盛んな場所ですから―
I'm sure we could earn a living
on one of your fanciful ideas.
きっと スバルくんの
とっぴな発想が―
生かせることもありますよ
And once our jobs were on track...
仕事が軌道に乗ったら―
Um, it's embarrassing to say,
その 恥ずかしいですけど
子供とか…
but we could have a child.
It would be half-demon and half-human,
鬼と人のハーフになるので
きっと わんぱくな子が生まれます
so I'm certain it would be feisty.
Whether we have a boy or a girl,
男の子でも 女の子でも―
twins or even triplets,
双子でも 三つ子でも
かわいい子になりますよ
I know they would be adorable.
I'm sure it wouldn't be all fun times.
きっと 楽しいことばかり
じゃないですし―
And not everything would work out as I imagined it.
こんなに想像どおりに―
うまくいくこと
ばかりじゃないと思います
We might have only daughters and no sons,
男の子が生まれずに―
女の子ばっかりが
続いてしまって―
so you might feel a little out of place in your family.
スバルくんが家庭内で―
肩身が狭くなることも
あるかもしれません
レム
Rem...
But still, even when the children grow up
でもでも 子供たちが
大きくなって―
and reach the age where they
start to treat you coldly,
スバルくんを邪険に扱うような
お年頃になっても―
I shall still be on your side!
レムはスバルくんの味方です
We will be famous in the neighborhood
as a couple of lovebirds,
ご近所では有名な おしどり夫婦
なんて言われてしまって―
as we take our time spending
life together and growing old.
ゆっくり 同じように時を過ごして
老いていって―
Rem...
レム…
I would feel bad for doing it to you,
（レム）
スバルくんには
ごめんなさいですけど―
できれば レムを
先に逝かせてください
but I would prefer to die before you, if possible.
I want to die quietly, lying on our bed,
with your hand in mine,
ベッドの上で
スバルくんに手を握られて―
surrounded by our children and their children.
子供たちや その子供たちに
囲まれて 静かに―
To say,
"I was so blessed,"
“レムは幸せでした”って
そう言って 見送られて
as you all watch my final moments.
I could end my life
happily, ever so happily.
幸せに幸せに
人生を終えることができるんです
If you've...
（スバル）そこまで…
If you've thought it through that far, then...
そこまで 思ってくれるなら…
If you could wish for that future with a smile,
（レム）
スバルくんが笑って
その未来を望んでくれるなら―
I would be truly happy to die that way.
レムは そうやって
死んでもよかったと―
本気で思います
As long as I could live with you.
スバルくんと
生きていけるなら―
Just knowing that you want me
with you when you run away
スバルくんが
逃げようと思った時―
レムと一緒にいたいと
思ってくれたことが―
makes me happy from the bottom of my heart.
今は心の底からうれしい
But I cannot.
でも ダメなんです
Because I know
だって きっと 今 一緒に
逃げてしまったら―
that if we run away together now,
I would be leaving behind
the Subaru-kun that I love most.
レムが１番好きな
スバルくんを―
置き去りにしてしまうような
気がしますから
Subaru-kun,
スバルくん 何があったのか
レムに話してください
please tell me what happened.
If you cannot, please trust me.
話せないのなら 信じてください
I swear I shall do something to make it right.
きっと レムが
どうにかしてみせます
でも せめて今は戻りましょう
But for now, at least, we should go back.
If we take our time, and consider things calmly,
ゆっくり時間をかけて
落ち着いて考えれば―
今とは違う答えが
見つかるかもしれません
maybe we will find a different answer.
I've already agonized over this.
もう悩んだんだ
考えたんだ 苦しんだんだ
I've thought about it.
I've suffered.
だから―
That's why...
I gave up.
諦めたんだ
It's easy to give up, but...
（レム）
諦めるのは簡単です
でも…
It's easy to give up?
（スバル）
諦めるのは簡単？
Subaru-kun?
スバルくん…
Don't give me that!
（スバル）ふざけるな！
There's nothing easy about giving up!
諦めるのが
簡単なわけねえだろうが！
You think I'm just doing nothing,
俺が何もしないで
何も考えないで―
emptying my head,
cutting myself off from everything,
ばっさり全部切り捨てて
あっさりと何もかも投げ捨てて―
and throwing it all away!?
And that's all it took to give up!?
それで諦めてるんだって
お前はそう思うのか！
It was not easy to give up!
諦めるのだって
簡単なんかじゃなかった！
It was so much easier for me to think
there was something I could do!
戦おうって
どうにかしてやろうって―
そう思うほうが
ずっと楽だったよ！
But there's nothing I can do!
だけど どうにもならないんだよ
道がどこにもないんだ！
There's no way out!
All the paths lead to one thing: giving up!
諦める道にしか続いてないんだ！
If I could do something,
何とかできるんなら―
俺だって… 俺だって！
I swear... I swear I would!
Subaru-kun...
スバルくん
It is easy to give up.
諦めるのは簡単です
でも―
But...
it doesn't suit you.
スバルくんには似合わない
I do not know what painful
things you've been through,
スバルくんが
どんなにつらい思いをしたのか―
or what you have come to know
that makes you suffer so.
何を知って
そんなに苦しんでいるのか―
レムには分かりません
And I know it would be wrong of me to thoughtlessly say I understand.
分かります なんて―
軽はずみに言っては
いけないとも思います
But...
でも それでも―
But even so...
There is something that I do know.
レムにだって
分かっていることがあります
I know that you're someone who cannot
give up on something halfway through.
スバルくんは―
途中で何かを諦めるなんて
できない人だってことです
I know that you are someone who can smile
レムは知っています
スバルくんは未来を望む時―
when you talk about your wishes for the future.
その未来を笑って話せる人だって
知っています
I know...
レムは知っています
スバルくんが 未来を
諦められない人だって知っています
I know that you are someone
who cannot give up on the future.
You're wrong.
違う… 俺は…
そんな人間じゃ…
I'm not that kind of—
I am not wrong.
（レム）違いません
You haven't given up on anyone.
スバルくんはみんなを―
Not Emilia-sama or Sister.
エミリア様も 姉様も
ロズワール様やベアトリス様―
Or Roswaal-sama, or Beatrice-sama, or anyone else.
ほかの人のことも
諦めてなんかいないはずです
I have... I have given up!
諦めた 諦めたよ
Carrying it all was impossible from the start!
全部拾うなんて
どだい無理なことだった！
My hands are so small,
俺の手のひらは小さくて
全部こぼれ落ちて―
that it all slipped through
my fingers, leaving nothing.
何も残らない
No, that isn't true.
（レム）
いいえ そんなことはありません
スバルくんには…
You have—
What do you know!?
（スバル）お前に―
俺の何が―
お前に 俺の何が
分かるっていうんだ！
What do you know about me!?
This is the kind of man I am!
俺は この程度の男なんだよ！
力なんてないのに
望みは高くて―
I have no strength, but I want it all.
I have no knowledge, but all I do is dream.
知恵もないくせに
夢ばかり見てて―
There's nothing I can do, but I struggle in vain!
できることなんてないのに
ムダにあがいて！
I... I...
俺は 俺は―
I hate myself!
俺が大っ嫌いだよ！
All I do is talk a big game,
いつだって口先ばっかりで―
and make myself sound like a big shot,
when I can't do anything!
何ができるわけでもねえのに
偉そうで―
I never do anything,
自分じゃ何もしねえくせに
文句つける時だけは一人前だ
yet I can complain like a pro.
Who the hell do I think I am!?
何様のつもりだ！
It's amazing that I can live like this
and not feel ashamed!
よくもまあ 恥ずかしげもなく
生きてられるもんだよな！
Right!?
なあ！
I'm empty.
空っぽだ　俺の中身はスカスカだ
There's nothing in me at all!
I know that.
決まってるさ　ああ 当たり前だ
Yeah, that's obvious.
I know it's obvious.
当たり前に決まってる
Before I came here...
俺が ここに来るまで―
Before I got into the situation
that led me to all of you,
こうして お前たちに
会うような事態になるまで―
do you have any idea what I did?
何をしてきたか分かるか！
I did nothing.
何もしてこなかった
I've never done a single thing.
何ひとつ
俺は やってこなかった
あれだけ時間があって
あれだけ自由があって―
I had all that time, all that freedom.
I could have done anything,
何だってできたはずなのに
何にもやってこなかった
but I never did a thing!
And this is the result!
その結果がこれだ！
What I am now is the result!
その結果が 今の俺だ！
All of my powerlessness, all of my incompetence,
俺の無力も 無能も
全部が全部―
is the product of my rotten character.
俺の腐りきった性根が理由だ
Wanting to accomplish something,
when I've never done anything,
何もしてこなかったくせに
何かを成し遂げたいだなんて―
goes beyond the limits of arrogance!
思い上がるにも
限度があるだろうよ！
The laziness and wasteful habits
I got from my pampered life
怠けてきたツケが
俺の盛大な人生の浪費癖が―
end up costing both of us our lives!
俺やお前を殺すんだ
That's right.
そうさ… 性根は何も
I have no character.
Even when I thought I could go on
living here, nothing changed.
この場所で生きてくんだって
そう思ったって―
何も変わっちゃいなかった
That old man saw that part of me perfectly.
あの爺(じい)さんは 俺のそこんとこも
きっちり見抜いてやがった
Right?
そうだろ
強くなろうとしてたわけでも―
I wasn't trying to get stronger
or trying to make things better.
どうにかなろうと
思ってたわけでもねえ
I was just striking an obvious pose to justify myself,
俺は ただ―
何もやってないわけじゃ
ないんだって―
to say that I was trying,
that I wasn't just sitting on my hands.
努力してるんだって―
そうやって
分かりやすいポーズをとって―
自分を正当化してただけだ！
I wanted to say there was nothing I could do!
しょうがないって言いたい
しかたがないって言われたい
I wanted to be told there was nothing I could do!
I only pretended to push my body
to the limit for that sole purpose!
ただ それだけのために―
俺はああやって 体を
張ってるようなふりをしてたんだ！
Even when I had you help me study,
お前をつきあわせて
勉強してたのだって―
I was just posing to cover up how embarrassed I felt!
そのバツの悪さをごまかすための
ポーズだったんだよ！
At heart,
俺の根っこは―
I'm just a small, cowardly, filthy piece of trash,
自分かわいさで 人の目ばっかり
気にしてるような―
who's always worried about how others see me.
小さくてひきょうで薄汚い
俺の根っこは 何も―
And nothing...
Nothing about me has changed!
何も変わらねえ！
I knew it all along.
本当は分かってたさ
That all of it was my fault...
全部 俺が悪いんだってことぐらい
I'm the lowest of the low.
俺は最低だ…
I can't stand myself.
俺は 俺が―
大嫌いだよ
I know...
（レム）
レムは知っています
That no matter how deeply
you have fallen into darkness,
スバルくんが どんなに
先の見えない暗闇の中でも―
you still have the courage
to reach out your hand.
手を伸ばしてくれる勇気が
ある人だってことを
I love it when you stroke my hair.
スバルくんに
頭をなでられるのが好きです
I feel as if we can understand each other
手のひらと髪の毛を通して―
through the contact between your hand and my hair.
スバルくんと通じ合っている
気がするんです
I love your voice.
スバルくんの声が好きです
Just hearing you say one word
言葉ひとつ聞くたびに
心が温かくなるのを感じるんです
makes my heart feel warmer.
I love your eyes.
スバルくんの目が好きです
Normally, they look stern,
普段は鋭いんですけど―
but when you're being kind to someone,
誰かに優しくしようと
している時―
I love the way they soften.
柔らかくなる
その目が好きです
I love your fingers.
スバルくんの指が好きです
For a boy, you have such lovely fingers.
男の子なのに
きれいな指をしていて―
But when they clutch mine,
I know they are the strong,
でも 握ると―
やっぱり男の子なんだって
思わせてくれる―
slender fingers of a man.
強くて細い指なんです
I love the way you walk.
スバルくんの歩き方が好きです
一緒に隣を歩いていると―
When we walk together,
I love the way you occasionally turn,
to make sure I'm keeping up.
たまに ちゃんと
ついてきているか―
確かめるみたいに
振り向いてくれる―
そんな歩き方が好きです
Stop...
（スバル）やめろ
I love the way you look when you sleep.
スバルくんの寝顔が好きです
You look unguarded, like an infant,
赤ん坊みたいに無防備で
まつ毛なんか ちょっと長くて―
and your eyelashes are on the long side.
When I touch your cheek, you calm down...
ほほに触れると
穏やかになって―
And when I playfully touch your lips,
you don't even notice...
いたずらで 唇に触れても
気づかなくって―
And it makes my heart ache terribly.
すごく胸が痛くなって
I love all of it.
好きです
どうして…
Why?
When you said that you hate yourself,
スバルくんが 自分のことを
嫌いだって そう言うのなら―
it made me want to tell you all
the wonderful things I know about you.
スバルくんのいいところが
こんなにあるって―
レムが知っていることを
知ってほしくなったんです
That's all just make-believe.
そんなものは まやかしだ
お前は分かってないだけだ！
You just don't know me!
I know myself better than anyone!
自分のことは 自分が１番
よく分かってる！
All you know is how you perceive yourself!
（レム）
スバルくんは
自分のことしか知らない！
How much do you know about
the Subaru-kun that I see!?
レムが見ている
スバルくんのことを―
スバルくんが
どれだけ知っているんですか！
Why... do you like me so much?
（スバル）
どうして そんなに…
俺は―
I'm weak and small.
俺は弱くてちっぽけで 逃げて―
I'm running away. Just like I did last time!
前の時も同じで逃げて
それでも どうして…
So why?
Because...
だって―
you are my hero, Subaru-kun!
スバルくんは
レムの英雄なんです
In that dark forest,
あの薄暗い森で―
when I didn't even know who I was anymore
自分のことも
分からなくなった世界で―
and couldn't think of anything
but violently lashing out,
ただ暴れまわることしか
考えられなかったレムを―
you saved me.
助けにきてくれたこと
When I woke up unable to move,
目を覚まして
動けないレムを―
and Sister was exhausted
after using too much magic,
魔法を使いすぎて
疲れきった姉様を―
you faced the witchfiends as a diversion,
so we could escape.
逃がすために おとりになって―
魔獣に立ち向かって
いってくれたこと
勝ち目なんてなくて
命だって 本当に危なくて―
There was no way you could win,
and your life was in real danger.
But still, you managed to survive
それでも生き残って
温かいまま―
and came back to my arms, alive and warm.
レムの腕の中に
戻ってきてくれたこと
When you woke up, you smiled,
目覚めて ほほえんで―
and said the words I wanted to hear most,
レムが１番ほしかった言葉を
１番言ってほしかった時に―
when I wanted to hear them most,
１番言ってほしかった人が
言ってくれたこと
from the one I wanted most to hear them from.
My time has been stopped for so long.
ずっと レムの時間は
止まっていたんです
Ever since that fiery night,
あの 炎の夜に―
the night I lost everything except my sister,
姉様以外の全てを失った
あの夜から―
my time has been stopped.
レムの時間は
ずっと止まっていたんです
It was you who melted my frozen heart,
止まっていた時間を
凍りついていた心を―
and kindly allowed me to begin moving forward again!
スバルくんが甘やかに溶かして
優しく動かしてくれたんです
I'm sure you have no idea just
how much you saved me,
あの瞬間に あの朝に
レムがどれだけ救われたのか―
レムがどんなに
うれしかったのか―
or how happy I was at that moment, on that fateful morning.
きっと スバルくんにだって
分かりません
That's why I believe.
だから レムは信じています
No matter what painful things happen,
どんなに
つらく 苦しいことがあって―
even when it looks like you're about to give in...
スバルくんが負けそうに
なってしまっても―
When no one else in the world believes in you,
世界中の誰もスバルくんを
信じなくなって―
when you don't even believe in yourself...
スバルくん自身も 自分のことが
信じられなくなったとしても―
I will believe!
レムは信じています
That the Subaru-kun who saved me
レムを救ってくれたスバルくんが
本物の英雄なんだって
is a true hero.
No matter how hard I tried,
どれだけ頑張っても
誰も救えなかった
I couldn't save anyone.
I am here.
（レム）レムがいます
The Rem you saved is right here.
スバルくんが救ってくれたレムが
今 ここにいます
（スバル）
何もしてこなかった
空っぽの俺だ
I've never done anything. I'm empty.
No one will even listen to me.
誰も耳を貸してなんかくれない
I am here.
レムがいます
I will listen to anything you have to say.
スバルくんの言葉なら
何だって聞きます
I want to.
聞きたいんです
No one expects anything of me.
誰にも期待されちゃいない
誰も俺を信じちゃいない
No one believes in me.
I hate myself.
俺は俺が大嫌いだ
Well, I love you, Subaru-kun!
レムは スバルくんを―
愛しています
You really don't mind that it's me?
俺なんかが… いいのか
I want it to be you.
スバルくんがいいんです
I would not want it to be anyone else.
スバルくんじゃなきゃ
イヤなんです
If you cannot forgive yourself for being empty and having nothing,
空っぽで 何もなくて
そんな自分が許せないなら―
then let us start from here, right now.
今 ここから始めましょう
Start what?
（スバル）何を…
Just like you started my time
for me when it was stopped,
（レム）
レムの止まっていた時間を―
スバルくんが
動かしてくれたみたいに―
we will make the time that
you feel is stopped for you
スバルくんが 止まっていると
思っていた時間を―
begin to move again.
今 動かすんです
Let us start here.
ここから始めましょう
From square one.
１から
いいえ―
No,
from zero!
ゼロから
If it is too hard for you to walk alone,
１人で歩くのが大変なら
レムが支えます
I will hold you up.
As we walk, we will share the burden
and support each other.
荷物を分けあって
お互いに支え合いながら歩こう
Wasn't this what you said to me that morning?
あの朝に
そう言ってくれましたよね？
Show me how awesome you can be, Subaru-kun.
かっこいいところを
見せてください スバルくん
（スバル）レム
Rem...
Yes?
はい
I love Emilia.
俺はエミリアが好きだ
Yes.
はい
I want to see Emilia smile.
（スバル）
エミリアの笑顔が見たい
I want to be of help to Emilia's future.
エミリアの
未来の手助けがしたい
Even if she says I'm in the way,
ジャマだって言われても
こないでって言われても―
even if she tells me to stay away...
I want to be next to her.
俺はあの子の隣にいたいよ
Using my feelings for her as an excuse
好きだからって
気持ちを免罪符にして―
to get her to understand everything
何でもかんでも
分かってもらおうって思うのは―
was arrogant of me, huh?
傲慢だよな
It's okay if she doesn't understand.
分かってもらえなくてもいい
I just want to save her.
今 俺はエミリアを助けたい
If there's a bleak, painful future waiting for her,
つらくて苦しい未来が
あの子を襲うんなら―
I want to take her away to a future
where we can all laugh together!
みんなで笑っていられる
未来に―
連れ出してやりたい
Will you help me?
手伝ってくれるか？
I can't do anything alone.
俺１人じゃ 何もできない
俺は何もかもが足りない
I lack in everything.
I'm not confident that I can
even keep walking straight.
まっすぐ歩けるような
自信がない
I'm weak, fragile, and small.
弱くて もろくて
ちっぽけだ
だから―
So,
to make sure I keep walking straight,
俺がまっすぐ歩けるように
間違っても気づけるように―
to help me realize when I'm wrong...
Will you help me?
手を貸してくれないか
You are a cruel man, Subaru-kun.
スバルくんは ひどい人です
You ask all this of someone you just rejected?
振ったばかりの相手に
そんなことを頼むんですか？
Hey, it's also hard for me to ask this of the person who rejected my once-in-a-lifetime proposal.
俺だって―
一世一代のプロポーズを
断られた相手に―
こんなこと 頼みづらいよ
I humbly accept.
謹んでお受けします
If it will help you,
それで スバルくんが―
レムの英雄が 笑って未来を
迎えられるのなら
my hero,
greet the future with a smile, then yes.
Yeah, just watch.
ああ 見ててくれ―
You get a front row seat...
特等席で！
To see the man you fell for
お前のほれた男が―
become the most awesome hero ever!
最高にかっこいいヒーローに
なるんだってところを！
I'm watching you.
（スバル）君を見てる
You're watching me.
君が見てる
So I won't look down anymore.
だから うつむかない
Natsuki Subaru's story will begin right here, from zero.
ここから ゼロから始めよう―
ナツキ･スバルの物語を
ゼロから始める
異世界生活を
My life in a different world starts here, from zero!
From   Zero